Emergency report!
（伝令）急報！ 左方より敵襲！
An enemy attack from the left!
その数100人
既に第２陣まで進行中
It's about 100 men!
They've already progressed to the second formation!
（馮忌(ふうき)）そうか　そういうことか
I see.
So that's what it is...?
王騎(おうき)
Wang Qi,
貴様のねらいは俺の首
your target is... my head?
面白い　取れるものなら取ってみろ
Interesting. If you think you can get it, go ahead and try!
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
時は紀元前 春秋戦国時代の秦国(しんこく)
The setting is before the common era,
in the State of Qin during the Spring and Autumn Warring States Period.
名もなき少年 信(しん)は
若き王 政(せい)と出会い―
The nameless boy Xin met with the young King Zheng,
武功を上げて
ついに 百人隊の将にまでなった
distinguished himself in war, and finally become a Hundred-Man General.
そんな中 突然 隣国の趙(ちょう)が攻め入り
未曽有の危機が訪れる
Among those events, the neighboring State of Zhao suddenly invaded,
presenting an unprecedented crisis.
総大将 王騎は
いかなる戦いを仕掛けるのか
What kind of war will Supreme Commander Wang Qi wage?
そして
信は いかなる成長を遂げるのか
And what kind of growth with Xin achieve?
Presented by Anime-Destiny
Translation
kewl0210
itsumo yori hayaku kietetta hoshi zora ni
いつもより早く消えてった星空に
In a starry sky that disappeared faster than it ever has
kusanariatta deai wa
重なり合った出会いは
the many piled up meetings we've had
Editing
jagman1x3
ore wo nomikonde iku
俺を呑み込んでいく
swallow me.
kono yume wa kudakenai
この夢は砕けない
This dream cannot be broken.
Timing
Seboo
sabitsukaseta kyoufushin
錆びつかせた恐怖心
Among this rusted fear in my heart
yuragu fuan no naka de
揺らぐ不安の中で
and the anxiety that makes me waver
Typesetting
G_I_A
ame wo saegiru shinjitsu
雨を遮る信実
is a truth that interrupts the rain.
dare ni mo ubaeyashinai
誰にも奪えやしない
No one can take it away,
Karaoke
kewl0210
FZeroWing
onaji keshiki ni hisonda puraido
同じ景色にひそんだプライド
our pride that lurks in the same landscape.
Encode
max80
itsuka kitto kanau ima mo mieru kibou fortitude
いつかきっと叶う 今も見える希望 fortitude
The fortuitous desire I have will definitely come true one day.
yowasa wo sute wa shinai
弱さを捨てはしない
We won't throw away our weaknesses,
oretachi no kienai shiin
俺達の消えないシーン
those are scenes that won't disappear.
furenzokusen no youni hashiru kibou unbreakable heart
不連続線の様に走る希望 unbreakable heart
My desire in my unbreakable heart runs like a discontinuous line.
I knew at the start that there's no end.
QC
Mistral[sA]
I've made up my mind, right now it's the time to take the first step.
Distro
kokus
Kittie
prefix-
Now's the only time.
～♪
Wang Qi's Flying Arrow
（尾到(びとう)）オリャ！
（沛浪(はいろう)）ンンッ！
（竜川(りゅうせん)）ンンッ！
（信）いける いける…
この調子なら いける
We can do it! We can do it!
If we keep this up, we can do it!
The method of a surprise attack where the enemy isn't prepared,
奇襲で虚をつくってやり方
that was a tactic Mr. Yuan and I used tons of times in that stateless area!
そいつは 無国籍地帯で
俺と渕(えん)さんが 繰り返し使った手だ
We were only protecting 100 tribe members.
俺らが守った部族は たったの100人
だから 正直 その手しかなかった
So honestly, that was the only trick we had.
けど おかげで 虚をつくってことの
威力は分かってるぜ
But thanks to that, we learned the power of surprise attacks!
（信）オリャー！
（尾平(びへい)）あっ…
W-We got through.
抜けた…
B-But the real problem is what comes next.
（魯延(ろえん)）だ… だが
これからが問題じゃ
Lu Yan
虚をつけたのも
ここまで
So far, we've attacked them while they were unprepared...
もはや その効力は うせた
but now that effect is gone.
あとの戦いは―
The battle now...
単純な力対力
will simply be strength versus strength.
（崇原(すうげん)）ンンッ…
Be careful!
気をつけろ
こいつら全員 相当 使うぞ
These guys all look pretty decent!
A Wu! Form a Wu!
（渕）伍(ご)だ！ 伍を作れ！
（尾平）ウワーッ！
ダメだ！
We're screwed!
（信）ンンッ！
（親衛隊員）ウワッ！
L-Lord Xin!
し… 信どの！
（斬る音）
（親衛隊員たち）ウワッ！
（渕）羌瘣(きょうかい)どの！
Lord Qiang Lei!
W-We have to fight!
や… やるしかない
Feixin Unit! Follow our general!
飛信(ひしん)隊！ 我が将に続け！
At this moment, the State of Qin's left army fight had become one sided.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）このとき 秦国左軍の
戦いは 一方的なものになっていた
矢の雨の中 後ろに走った秦国軍は
Running away under a rain of arrows, the State of Qin Army was
趙国の掃討隊に
徹底的に背を射(う)たれたのだ
being thoroughly beaten by the State of Zhao's Cleanup Unit.
干央(かんおう)と壁(へき)の部隊 およそ1,500は
前進し 難を逃れたものの―
Gan Yang and Bi's units of about 1,500 were marching forward and escaping the hardship,
秦国左軍の大部分は
この追い討ちにやられた
but the vast majority of the State of Qin's left army was being routed and beaten.
生き残った左軍の兵は
３割程度となり―
No more than 30% of the original left army survived.
趙兵は それをゆっくりと追った
And the Zhao soldiers leisurely chased after them.
しかし この状況にもかかわらず
王騎は動かなかった
But in spite of this state of affairs, Wang Qi did not move.
くそ… 敵が強すぎる
Shit...
The enemy... is too strong...
（尾平）おまけに こっちは
疲労で意識が遠くなってきやがった
Plus, we're so fatigued...
My consciousness is fading...
目が かすむ…
My eyes are... getting hazy...
今にも ぶっ倒れそうだ…
I feel like I'm about to collapse already...
ハァ…
だが… だが しかし…
But... But...
（尾到）
あいつが斬る度に 力が湧いてくる
Every time he cuts someone, my strength comes back!
Every time our general cuts down an enemy...
（尾到）
俺らの大将が敵をぶった斬る度に！
再び 全身に力が みなぎる！
power surges throughout our bodies again!
What's with these guys...?
（親衛隊副長）何だ？ こいつら
（親衛隊長）この百人隊の将は
あの手だれの小僧か
The general of this Hundred-Man Unit is such a skilled kid...?
しかも 驚くべきことに 完全に
部隊の精神的支柱となっている
And amazingly, he seems to be a pillar holding up his unit's spirit.
しかし 士気だけでは 我ら親衛隊を
破ることは 決してできませぬ
But mere morale will never be enough to break through our elite guards!
そうだ
That's right.
あやつら
このまま消耗戦を続ければ―
If they keep up this war of attrition,
いずれ すり減り 消滅する
they'll eventually get worn down and collapse.
よって 我らの勝利は動かん
The certainty of our victory shall not change!
進め進め！ 進めー！
Forward! Forward!
Forward!
くそ！ このまま戦っていても
ラチが明かねえ！
Shit. Even if we keep fighting like this, we're not making any progress!
けど 一体 どうすれば…
What the hell can we do...?
アッ… アア… 副将！
Vice General!
What is it, Lu Yan?!
どうした？ 魯延どの
このままでは
どうにもなりませんぞ
Continuing like this will get us nowhere!
分かっている　しかし
今は この敵を撃破せぬことには…
I know!
But right now, unless we make our way through these enemies...
（魯延）そこでじゃよ
In regards to that...
た… 確かに それしかない
Y-You're right, that's our only chance.
（渕）信どの！
Lord Xin! I'm sorry!
御免ーっ！
何すんだ こんなときに！
（渕）すいません… ですが―
What're you doing at a time like this?!
Sorry,
but this is urgent!
至急 お話が
（信）隊を分離する？
Split up... the unit?
そうです
このまま消耗戦を続けても―
Yes!
If this war of attrition keeps going, we'll eventually all run out of strength
いずれ力尽き
ここを突破することはできない
and we won't be able to break through here.
So while we have the chance, we break up this Hundred Man Unit into two units,
ならば 今のうちに この百人隊を
精鋭の部隊と
そうでない部隊の２つに分け
an elite unit and a lesser unit.
後者の部隊に
この場の敵を引き付けさせ
The rear unit will draw the attention of the enemy to this area,
and the elite unit should head toward the location of Zhao General, Feng Ji.
精鋭部隊を
趙将 馮忌のもとへ送るべきです
引き付けさせて…
Draw their attention...?
ちょっと待てよ　んなことしたら
ここに残るヤツらは全滅するぞ
Hold on a second!
If we do that, the guys that stay behind will be wiped out!
Never mind that!
かまいません！
なんだと！
What?!
（渕）飛信隊の任務は
この場の敵を討つことでも―
The Feixin Unit's mission is not to attack the enemy in this area
nor is it to bring all 100 members back alive.
100人全員が生還することでもない
趙将 馮忌を討つことです
It is to defeat the Zhao General, Feng Ji!
それさえ かなえば―
As long as we achieve that, even if our unit is reduced by half or more,
たとえ部隊が半数以下になろうとも
飛信隊の勝利
it will be the Feixin Unit's victory!
そのための礎となるのなら
我々は喜んで ここに残れます！
If we can be the foundation of that,
then we will gladly remain here!
ハッ…“我々”？
We?
ハハッ… 私は残ります
I'll stay behind!
この場で戦う者たちにも
将は必要ですからね
The people fighting here will need a general, after all.
渕さん…
（澤圭(たくけい)）信君
Mr. Yuan...
Young Xin!
（澤圭）渕副将の言うとおり
我らには気兼ねなく行ってください
It is just as Vice General Yuan says.
Don't worry about us, just go, please!
（信）澤さん
Mr. Ze...
Just as you said, Young Xin.
信君が言ったとおり これは
勝たなくてはいけない戦いですよ
This is a battle we absolutely must win!
それに 私を含め
多くが もうそろそろ限界です
And many of us are almost at our limits, myself included.
精鋭部隊さえ抜けていけば
あとは こんな所に用はありません
If only an elite unit escapes,
then there will no longer be a need for anyone here.
我々も
さっさと ここを離脱しますよ
We will withdraw from here as well, without delay.
逃げるだけなら 我々でも
十分できますから 是非 早く
If it's running away we need to do, then we're more than capable.
Please, you must hurry.
澤さん…
Mr. Ze...
It's a bluff.
（渕）虚勢だ… この敵陣からの
脱出は たやすくない
Escaping from this enemy formation would be no easy feat.
だが さすがに信どのの元伍長
これで 信どのは―
But since that came from Lord Xin's former Wuchang
I would expect Lord Xin will be able to act!
行ける！
（信）ンンッ…
（信）まだ走れる伍を…
The Wu that can still run...
沛浪！ 田永(でんえい)！
Pei Lang! Tian Yong!
The Wu that can still fight...
まだ戦える伍を…
中鉄(ちゅうてつ)！ 去亥(きょがい)！ 竜有(りゅうゆう)！ 邦(ほう)！
Zhong Tie! Qu Hai! Long You! Bang!
まだ気力が衰えていない伍を…
The Wu that still haven't lost their vigor!
田有(でんゆう)！ 竜川！ 尾平！ 尾到！
Tian You! Long Chuan! Wei Ping! Wei Dao!
Bring everyone in your Wu that can fight and come with me!
各伍長は 戦えるヤツを引き連れて
俺についてこい！
（田有）
百人隊を２つに分けるのか？
We're splitting the Hundred Man Unit in two?
いや それでいい
もう それしかない
No, that's fine.
That's our only plan now.
羌瘣！ 羌瘣は どこだ！
Qiang Lei!
Where's Qiang Lei?!
渕さん
（渕）はい！
Mr. Yuan!
Yes?!
俺らが行ったら
何が何でも ここを逃げきれ
When we're gone, get out of here no matter what comes your way!
We'll definitely meet up again after!
絶対 あとで また会うぞ
馮忌の顔を拝ませてやる
I'll make Feng Ji bow his head to me!
I wish you the fortunes of battle!
ご武運を
そっちもな　行くぞ！
You, too.
Let's go!
Do you think we'll let you State of Qin dogs escape?!
秦国の犬どもが！ 誰が行かせるか
We will get through!
（三和(さんか)）行かせるんだよ！
And we're looking forward to taking your general's head!
お前ら！
大将首 楽しみにしているぞ！
（沛浪）任せとけ！
Leave this to me!
アアッ！
（親衛隊副長）隊長！
Captain!
馮忌ーっ！
Feng Ji!
（王騎）
剣の戦いに間合いがあるように―
Just like how one maintains a distance from one's opponent in a sword fight,
軍を率いる将も また
独自の戦いの間合いを持ちます
a general leading an army also has his own fighting space.
その範囲の中で
将の能力は いかんなく発揮される
A general's full ability is displayed when one is within that range.
馮忌の間合いは
中距離から長距離でしょう
Feng Ji's space is from mid-range to long-range, isn't it?
（騰(とう)）はっ！ そのようです
Yes, so it would seem.
（王騎）そう あの距離は
馮忌の間合いから外れていますねえ
Yes. And that range deviates from Feng Ji's space, isn't it?
ココココッ…
（騰）はっ！ 近すぎます
Yes, sir. It is too close.
I'm counting on you, Youngster Xin.
アテにしてますよ 童 信
私の飛矢
My flying arrow...
（馮忌）
フン… 横撃した小隊は どうした？
What's come of that small unit that attacked from the side?
（副官１）
いまだ交戦中のようですが
敵影は 既に半分です
They still seem to be in mid-battle,
but their number has already been reduced to half.
（馮忌）フッ… 終わったな
So it's over, is it?
（副官１）はい
Yes, sir!
（信）あれが本陣か
So that's... the headquarters?!
バ… バカな！
親衛隊が抜かれたのか？
I-Impossible!
They got through the elite guard?!
（副官２）いや まだ交戦中だ
（副官１）どういうことだ？
No, they're still fighting!
What do you mean?!
So they split their 100 in two.
（馮忌）100人を２つに分け―
仲間半分の命を盾として
ここへ来たか
They used half their comrades as a shield to get here, did they?
It's the headquarters.
本陣だ
（中鉄）ついに来たぞ ここまで
We finally... made it here...
ぶっ殺す
（尾到）羌瘣 敵の数は？
Let's kill them.
Qiang Lei, what're the enemy's numbers?
（羌瘣）200～300…
Two to three hundred.
30対300か…
（沛浪）心配すんな
So it's 30 versus 300, huh?
Don't worry.
馮忌より こっち側は150人
縦に15 横に10
There's only 150 on this side of Feng Ji.
It's 15 across and 10 wide.
In other words, if we can cut through 10 men, we can get to the general's head.
つまり
10人斬り込めば 大将首ってことだ
しゃ！ そんなら いけるぞ！
（尾到）おう！
All right!
That, we can make!
よし 待ってろよ 渕さんたち
覚悟しやがれ 馮忌！
Okay. Wait for us, Mr. Yuan, everybody...
And prepare yourself, Feng Ji!
行くぞ てめえら！
Let's go, bastards!
王騎将軍が
序盤戦で最重要だと言ったこの戦い
General Wang Qi said that this battle, the opening phase is the most important one!
We're going to end it with our own hands!
俺たちの手で 終わらせるぞー！
（兵士たち）オーッ！
（副官１）突撃してくるぞ
They're charging.
Do you seriously think they'll make it all the way here?
本気で ここまで来られると
思っているのか？
あるいは 華々しく散るつもりか？
（馮忌）いや 来る
Or do you think they're planning to scatter in a showy fashion?
No, they'll come.
えっ？
（馮忌）ヤツらは ここまで来る
They'll come here.
（守備隊長）たかが30で
この本陣に挑んでくるとは…
Those 30 people are challenging this entire headquarters formation?
歩兵 構え！
Foot soldiers, at the ready!
Send those death-dodging bastards to the next world!
（守備隊長）死に損ないどもを
あの世に送ってやれ！
（馮忌）ごく稀(まれ)に 戦場にて人は
常識を超えた力を宿すときがある
In extremely rare cases, there are times when people hold
a power that goes beyond the boundaries of conventional thinking.
理詰めの将ほど
そういう者に足をすくわれやすい
The more logical the general, the more easily they slip against such people.
敵に ここまで迫られたのは
正直 初めてだ
This is honestly the first time an enemy has gotten this close to me,
だが
たまには こういう戦も悪くない
but it's not a bad thing to have battles like this on occasion.
（趙兵）
何をやっているか！ 行かせるな！
What're you doing?! Don't let them through!
（趙兵）止めろー！
Stooop!
ええい どけい！ このわしが
じきじきに葬ってくれるわ！
Out of the way!
I'll bury them myself!
（趙兵）収(しゅう)さま！
Lord Shou!
ハアーッ！
ガキがー！
You brat!
（斬る音）
ウワッ！
（副官１）趙覚(ちょうかく)隊 趙告(ちょうこく)隊 前へ出よ
Zhao Jue Unit, Zhao Gao Unit, move forward!
騎馬兵がいて
なぜ 30人ごとき止められぬ！
Why can't the mounted soldiers stop a mere thirty people?!
さっさと討ち取らぬか！
Would you hurry and take them down?!
たかが数十といえど―
Though they only number in the dozens,
あそこまで勢いに乗られると
手がつけられませぬなぁ
to use their momentum means they are quite untouchable, yes?
本陣が騎馬主体というのも
裏目に出ましたねえ
The down side to having a headquarters mostly made up of mounted soldiers has shown its face.
Horses are used for running.
騎馬は 走ってこそのもの
密集地に とどまっているなら
その力は発揮しませんよ
Gathered into a crowd, they cannot utilize that strength.
策士 馮忌は
ここから何か講じるでしょうか？
What do you think that schemer Feng Ji is planning to do next?
ンフッ… ムリでしょう
There's nothing, really.
あの距離まで詰められては
策を施す余地はありません
Cramped into that position, there's no room for any plans.
Especially for Feng Ji...
特に 馮忌には…
It's true that interring the majority of the Qin left army was skillful,
確かに 秦国左軍の大半を
葬った手腕は鮮やかでしたが
but in exchange for that,
しかし その代償に 馮忌は
飛信隊を懐深く侵入させてしまった
Feng Ji allowed the Feixin Unit to penetrate deep into his bosom.
Against someone as unskilled at close-range battles as Feng Ji,
近距離戦が不得手な馮忌にとって
飛信隊の見落としは―
overlooking the Feixin Unit will turn out to be an irrecoverable misstep.
取り返しのつかない痛手です
このまま決着ですか？
（王騎）そうですねえ…
Will it continue like this to a conclusion?
I would say so.
まあ まだ馮忌にも
この状況を挽回する方法が―
Though, I suppose there is still one way for Feng Ji to weasel his way out of this situation...
ひとつだけありますけどね
（信）しゃ！ 抜けた！
All right! We got though!
（尾平）ハァ… 抜けた
Through?
抜けた …ぞ
We got... through?
（王騎）
馮忌が挽回する ただひとつの方法
The one method Feng Ji can use to recover...
それは…
is...
再び 距離を作ることです
to regain the distance he lost.
Y-You're kidding, right?
（尾平）ウ… ウソだろう…
しょ… 将軍のくせに…
150もいるのに…
Even though he's a general...
Even though he's got 150 men...
They're retreating from the 30 of us?
30人の俺たちから逃げるのか？
止まれ　十分だ
（副官１）全軍 停止！
Stop. That's enough.
All units, halt!
（王騎）
さすがですねえ　この一手で―
Just what I'd expect from him.
With that one tactic, Youngster Xin has been brought to the jaws of death.
童 信は
死地に たたき落とされました
If he sends out the mounted units from that range
あの距離から騎馬隊を繰り出せば
歩兵など ひとたまりもありません
not one foot soldier will be left standing.
そうですねえ ンフッ…
Yes, indeed...
マ… マズイ　前後から攻められた
（田有）ど… どうする？
This is bad!
We're gonna be attacked from behind!
Wh-What do we do?
ンンッ… 完全に行き詰まった
とにかく ここを脱出しねえと
We're totally cornered...
Right now, we need to get out of here or...
だけど―
Maybe Qiang Lei and I could manage something, but...
俺と羌瘣なら
なんとかなるかもしんねえが
こいつらはムリだ…
these guys don't have a chance!
（尾平）い… 行け 信
G-Go... Xin...
お前と羌瘣なら… 抜けられる…
You and Qiang Lei... can make it... out.
行け！
Go!
何言ってやがるんだ！
お前 ふざけて…
What're you talking about?!
Don't go screwing around-
ふざけてねえ！
行けっつってんだ バカ野郎！
I'm not screwing around!
I told you to go, you fucking moron!
お前は ここで死ねねえだろうが！
天下の大将軍になるんだろうが！
You can't die here!
You're gonna become the greatest general under the heavens, aren't you?!
ダメだ
（尾平）ハッ…
I can't.
信！ このままじゃ終わりなんだぞ
Xin!
If you don't do something, this is the end!
行けよ！
Go!
行けるかよ
How could I?
I'm sorry, Qiang Lei.
すまねえ 羌瘣…
（羌瘣）謝るな
Don't apologize.
まだ終わってない
It's not over yet.
な… なに！
ふ… 馮忌さま 正面から！
Wh-What?!
L-Lord Feng Ji, from the front!
（尾平）左軍だ…
The left army...
左軍の騎馬が 趙の防壁から！
The left army mounted soldiers are coming through the Zhao defensive wall!
（中鉄）
40… 50… どんどん出てくるぞ！
40... 50... They keep coming and coming!
干央だ！
（尾平）知ってんのか？
It's Gan Yang!
You know him?!
王騎将軍の側近のひとり
多分 あれが左軍の将だ
He's one of Wang Qi's close aides.
He's probably the general of the left army!
I'm here for your head, Feng Ji!
（干央）首をもらいに来たぞ 馮忌
ンンッ… こしゃくな
Impudent fool...
Call the right half!
右の半数を呼べ
今度は何だ！
What is it this time?!
干央隊を援護！ 敵歩兵を
本陣 および 干央隊に近づけるな！
Backup the Gan Yang Unit!
Do not let the enemy foot soldiers near their headquarters or near the Gan Yang Unit!
壁のあんちゃんまで ヘヘッ…
Even Brother Bi is here.
All units, charge!
（干央）全軍 突撃ーっ！
They finally made it though, it seems.
ようよう抜けましたな
（王騎）フフフフッ…
俺たちも行くぞ！
（兵士たち）オーッ！
We're going, too!
将軍が言ったとおりになったぞ 信
（信）えっ？
It went just the way the general said, Xin!
最初に言っただろう
“敵と左軍が戦っている際”
He said it back at the beginning!
While the enemy and the left army are fighting,
“その どさくさに紛れて
将を討て”と
we would slip though the confusion and take the general's head!
（尾到）今が その時だ
Now's that moment!
俺たちの足に合わせるな！
全速で馮忌将軍の首を取りに行け！
Don't slow down on our account!
Go at full speed to take General Feng Ji's head!
尾到…
（尾到）早く行け！
Wei Dao...
Hurry, go!
You've got to take the general's head, Xin!
大将の首は お前が取るんだ 信！
分かった　大将首は俺が取る！
Got it!
That general's head is mine!
だが みんな 聞け！
手柄は俺がもらうが恩賞は山分けだ
But everyone, listen up!
I'll be taking the achievement,
but we're splitting the reward equally!
生きてるヤツも 死んでるヤツも
全員まとめて100等分だ！
The living and the dead,
all get one hundredth of the total!
Go!
行けー！
Captain!
（羌瘣）信…
（信）何だ？
Xin.
What?
将に近づいたら 一瞬の隙を狙え
それを逃(のが)すな　機は必ずある
When you get close to the general, aim for a moment's opening.
Don't let it slip away.
There will definitely be a chance.
分かってる
Got it.
仲間か…
Comrades, huh...?
ヤッ！
（趙兵）ウワッ！
What are you acting so proud of?
（馮忌）何を得意げになっている？
左軍の将
それで追い詰めたつもりか？
Left army general, do you think you've cornered me?
俺の戦術に誤りはない
There are no errors in my strategy.
だが 戦術に誤りがなくとも
物事に 僅かな誤差が生じてしまう
But even without any strategical errors,
small errors in calculation manifest themselves.
That is the nature of actual battle.
実戦とは そういうものだ
今の この状況は―
The current state of affairs is nothing but the result of overlapping good luck they've had from that error in calculation.
その誤差が ヤツらにとって
運よく重なっただけだ
運？
Luck?
いや どうも腑(ふ)に落ちぬ
No.
That simply doesn't explain it.
Would I allow my enemies to get this close to me merely on luck?
運だけで この俺が
これほど 敵の肉薄を許すか？
Does that mean there was an error in my strategy?
俺の戦術に
誤りがあったというのか？
It's him...
あいつだ… あの横撃してきた小隊
あれに本陣を崩された
and that platoon that attacked from the side.
My headquarters is broken apart because of them.
But among the tactics with an army of 10,000 versus an army of 10,000,
だが 万対万の戦術の中で―
百人隊の快進撃など
それこそ 誤差のひとつにすぎぬ
the advancement of a Hundred Man Unit is nothing more than part of that error in calculation.
第一
あの小隊が本陣に届いたのは偶然だ
First, that platoon reaching the headquarters was a coincidence.
If I hadn't opened both wings in order to inter the State of Qin left army,
秦国左軍を葬るため
俺が両翼を上げなければ―
ヤツらは入ってこられなかった
they wouldn't have gotten in.
ハッ！
両翼が上がるから小隊は放たれた？
Did the platoon break off because the wings opened?!
俺は 両翼を上げさせられた？
Was I pushed towards opening the wings?!
Did that man send the left army of 10,000 charging in order to achieve that...?!
そうさせるために 左軍１万を
突撃させたのだ あの男は
小隊の進撃は偶然ではない
The advance of the platoon is not a coincidence.
俺は 第１手で既に
あの男の術中に はまっていた…
With my first move, I had already fallen for that man's tricks...!
馮忌は
戦術好きがアダとなりましたな
Feng Ji's love of tactics has backfired on him, hasn't it?
大技に出るには
注意が足りませんでしたねえ
He lacked the caution to use those bold moves.
攻めが
大好きなんでしょう 馮忌さんは
That Feng Ji just loves attacking, doesn't he?
たまには受けも意識しないと
But you occasionally need the a sense for defense.
To have manipulated the left battlefield without even leading it, you are quite the genius, Lord.
率いずとも
左の戦場を操られた殿は 天才です
ンフフフッ… 意外と私も―
Believe it or not, I actually don't mind them.
嫌いじゃありませんからねえ
長距離戦が
Long distance battles.
ンンッ… 下がるぞ！
We're retreating!
馮忌さま…
（馮忌）残兵処理に興味はない
Lord Feng Ji!
I have no interest in dealing with these remnants.
前の防壁と共に
お前たちで片づけろ
You and the forward defensive wall take care of them.
The rear soldiers and I will be making a temporary retreat to the thicket.
俺は 後ろの兵と共に
茂みの中まで 一時 後退する
Yes, sir!
That's far enough, Feng Ji!
ここまでだ 馮忌！
我が主(あるじ)の前で 策をひけらかすのは
十年早かったな
You're ten years early to try to show off a plan in front of me!
ほざけ
策に溺れたのは貴様らのほうだ
Nonsense!
You're the one's conceited with your plans!
その証拠に ここに
たどりついたのは貴様らだけ
The proof of that is your group reached here alone.
貴様を殺し 残る兵を皆殺しにして
左軍を完全に葬ってくれる！
I'll kill you, slaughter the remaining soldiers, and inter the entire left army!
That will never happen.
ムリだな
貴様の命運は もう尽きた
Your fate...
has already been sealed.
それは こちらの言うセリフだ
その男を殺せ！
I should be the one saying that to you!
Kill that man!
Feng Ji...
馮忌
殿の飛矢が…
The Lord's flying arrow...
届くぞ
has reached its target.
（斬る音）
ウワッ！
ウワッ…
と… 取ったぞ…
I... I got it...
michi wa tsuzuku yume wo oimotome
路は続く　夢を追い求め
The path goes on, chasing after a dream.
nozomu saki ni kimi no ashita wa aru no?
望む先に　君の明日はあるの？
Will your tomorrow be at the place my hopes lead?
kizutsuite kokoro mo mada kawaku nara
傷ついて　心もまだ渇くなら
If I get hurt and my heart is still thirsty,
koko e kite nando demo utau kara
ここへ来て何度でも歌うから
I'll come here and sing as many times as it takes.
owari naki tatakai no naka de
終わりなき戦いの中で
In this endless battle
kimi wa tsuyoku kawaru
君は強く変わる
You change to become stronger.
kono sora wo kirisaita ikazuchi wa kimi
この空を切り裂いた　雷は君
The lightning that cut apart this sky is you.
osore wo koete tachimukau hikari no ya hashiridasu
恐れを超えて立ち向かう　光の矢　走りだす
The arrow of light that overcomes fear faces forward and shoots forth.
tsukamu sadame shinjitsuzukeru no...
掴む　運命　信じ続けるの…
I'll grab onto the destiny I've always believed in...
～♪
Preview
（貂(てん)）李白(りはく)軍の陣形が変わっていく
The Li Bai Army's formation... is changing!
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）全ては整った
最強の男が 戦場を食らう
Everything is in order!
The strongest man devours the battlefield!
Sudden Change in
the Tide of Battle
Next time,
次回 “戦局急転”
Sudden Change in
the Tide of Battle
End